Why didn't you take the client
赵方刚给你介绍的客户
Zhao Fanggang introduced?
为什么不接
The shipyard project fell through,
造船厂的项目黄了
and now you're doubting yourself,
你就不相信自己
questioning your abilities,
怀疑自己的能力
aren't you?
不是吗
You should focus on
还是把自己的事情
your own issues now.
管好再说吧
So, it's fine being just
所以一直当助理
an assistant?
也没关系
It's fine if you don't pass
转正考核
the assessment?
不通过也没关系
Right!
没关系
This is my level.
我就这水平了
I don't have your instincts.
我没有你们的敏感度
Every client
我现在看所有的客户
seems to be problematic,
都觉得有问题
but I can't pinpoint
但是我又不知道
what's wrong.
问题出现在哪里
What can I do?
那能怎么办呢
Is that really how you see yourself?
这就是你对自己的评价
You didn't use to be like this.
涂筱柠你以前不这样
You've changed.
你变了
Yes, I have!
我变了
People sure change.
人就是会变的
Look at you now.
你看看你现在
You're not
你现在变得
the man I knew
也不是我一开始认识的
in the beginning.
那个纪昱恒了呀
[Ji Yuheng, you're avoiding this issue.]
纪昱恒你在逃避问题
[You can't face your mom's illness]
你不敢面对妈的病情
[or the worst possible outcome.]
你不敢面对最坏的结果
[You keep saying you're out]
每天拿着
[earning money for her medicine.]
出去赚钱买药当幌子
[Then you're never around.]
却找不到人
[You're just]
其实呢
[making excuses.]
你就是在给自己找借口
[Ji Yuheng, right?]
纪昱恒 是吧
[I've heard]
我其实
[bits and pieces]
听到过你的一些事情
[about you.]
就是偶尔听别人说起
[I'm not sure about that.]
确实也不是很清楚
[But I wanna tell you,]
但是我就是想跟你说
[you should move forward.]
凡事你得往前看
[Looking back,]
你一直往后看
[it's inevitable to face loss.]
就经常面对失去
[But if you look ahead,]
但是往前看的话
[you'll find]
就会有很多
[new opportunities.]
不一样的收获
[And you?]
那你呢
[Why didn't you take the client]
赵方刚给你介绍的客户
[Zhao Fanggang introduced?]
为什么不接
[The shipyard project fell through,]
造船厂的项目黄了
[and now you're doubting yourself,]
你就不相信自己
[questioning your abilities,]
怀疑自己的能力
[aren't you?]
不是吗
Am I avoiding it?][
我是在逃避吗
[What if]
如果
[I just can't]
我就是干不好
[do this job well?]
这个工作呢
It's the weekend.
今天是周末
Aren't you
你
planning to visit the hospital?
不打算去医院吗
I have a client meeting today.
我今天约了一个客户
I'll go after I'm done.
等忙完了之后就过去
It's my bad yesterday.
昨天是我不对
Visiting hours
医院那边下午四点
end at 4:00 p.m.
就不允许探望了
If you wanna go,
你如果想去的话
you should hurry.
抓点紧
Mom.
妈
How are you feeling today?
今天感觉怎么样啊
Did the lady in the bed
旁边床
next to you get discharged?
阿姨出院了
She passed away
昨天晚上
last night.
人走了
So suddenly?
这么突然
I saw her just days ago.
我看她前两天
She looked great
还挺精神的
and always greeted me.
每次来都跟我打招呼
The paperwork is done.
手续已经办完了
Let's go home.
我们回去吧
Don't be too upset.
别太难过了
[I didn't even get to see her]
我连她最后一面
[one last time.]
都没赶上
Mom,
妈
I've talked to the doctor.
那个我问医生了
He told me
医生说
that your condition
咱们这两天
has improved a lot.
恢复得特别好
You're feeling better too,
你自己也感觉挺好的
right?
对吧
I'm not afraid of dying.
妈不是怕死
At my age,
这个年纪了
I've seen plenty
生生死死
of life and death.
见得多了
I'm just worried about you.
妈是担心你们
No worries.
不担心
Yuheng
昱恒
has been busy
他这两天
with business lately,
有很多事情要处理
but he said
但是他说了
he would
今天
definitely come today.
今天肯定会来
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
I'm thinking...
妈想
If you're available
你们这两天
in the next
如果有空
couple of days,
方便的话
could you help
把那老宅子
tidy up the old house?
给我收拾出来吧
I wanna move back there.
我想搬回去住
You wanna be discharged?
您想出院啊
I've been
你看我这两天
feeling great.
精神挺好的
With the
坚持 坚持
nurse's help,
有护工扶着我
I can even take a few steps.
还能走几步呢
I'm just afraid
我是怕
that when the time really comes,
等真到了最后那几天
I won't be able to go back home.
想回家回不了了
This place
这里啊
is cold and unwelcoming,
冷冰冰的
unlike home.
不像家里
If you wanna go home,
想出院就出院嘛
we'll help tidy up.
我去帮你收拾
Don't talk like that.
你别说这样的话呀
Alright, alright.
好 好 好
Silly child.
傻孩子
[Sorry,]
您好
[the subscriber you dialed is busy now.]
您所呼叫的用户正忙
[Please try again later.]
请您稍后再拨
[Mom just said]
妈刚才说
[she wanna go home.]
她想要出院回家住
[If it's]
如果
[really her]
这真的是妈
[last stretch,]
生命的最后一段时光
[spending it in the hospital]
在医院度过
[would leave her with regrets.]
她会有遗憾
Actually,
其实
the executive lounge
我们酒店的
at our hotel,
行政酒廊
with its design and management system,
装修风格和管理系统
is already at
已经完全可以达到了
a five-star level.
五星级标准
Once the loan is approved,
这贷款到账后
we'll be able
我们再在硬件
to make some major upgrades
和配套设施上
to the hardware and facilities,
做一些大的提升
aiming for a rating
评级是完全
that could even surpass five stars.
可以超五星的
Given our
加上我们
unique location
在星城
in this city,
独一无二的地理优势
the returns
这收成
are practically guaranteed.
是完全没有问题的
I understand that.
您说的这些我都明白
I've reported to the headquarters.
我也跟总部汇报过了
Regarding our partnership with Zhouyang,
在和洲洋的合作上
our bank
我们代瑞
is fully committed.
是有绝对的诚意的
Mr. Chen,
陈总
what tea would you like today?
您今天想要什么茶
[Mom just said]
妈刚才说
[she wanna go home.]
她想要出院回家住
[If it's]
如果
[really her]
这真的是妈
[last stretch,]
生命的最后一段时光
[spending it in the hospital]
在医院度过
[would leave her with regrets.]
她会有遗憾
Initially, we're more inclined
其实我们一开始
to work with Bank of Xinfa.
更想跟信发合作
their terms for the loan cycle
信发在打款周期
and repayment period
和还款时限上
are more favorable
给出的条件
than yours.
都比代瑞好
But the fact that you traveled
但是你能不远千里
all the way to our headquarters
跑了趟我们总部
and met with
还见到了
our direct supervisor
我们直属负责人
shows your dedication.
也算挺有本事的
As you mentioned,
其实您刚才也说了
once Zhouyang is upgraded,
洲洋升星之后
the revenue pressure
其实对于营收上的压力
won't be significant,
并没有很大
so the loan term
贷款时限
isn't the most
对于洲洋来说
critical factor.
也并不是最核心的问题
Dairui is more focused
我们代瑞更希望的
on enhancing the financing
是能够完善洲洋
to your supply chain.
在供应链上的融资
I know you're
我大致了解了一下
expanding
洲洋是在
your scale in 6 cities
全国的六个城市
across the country.
同时扩大规模
It places
这对于
considerable pressure
上游的供应商来说
on upstream suppliers.
其实压力是不小的
We can offer
我们代瑞可以根据
loan amounts
具体的需求
to these suppliers
给上游的供应商
based on specific needs,
提供贷款额度
ensuring a stable
从而保证酒店
supply chain for the hotel
供应链上的关联企业
and the steady operation
能够稳定供货
of related businesses.
和稳定经营
I believe this is
我相信这对于洲洋来说
the key for you.
是最为关键的一点
You're worthy of the reputation.
纪经理果然名不虚传
You flatter me.
您过奖了
If we're lucky to collaborate,
要是有幸合作
the signing
签约地方
will take place
还是在我们
at our headquarters.
京海总部
You might have to make
到时候恐怕还得劳烦你
another trip.
再跑一趟了
No problem at all.
当然没问题
I've already emailed you
我已经把整体的
the overall
贷款方案
loan proposal.
发到你邮箱了
Would now be a good time to review it?
您看现在方不方便
No need to rush.
着什么急呀 纪经理
Try some
尝一尝
of our refreshments.
我们洲洋的茶点
You know,
今天周末
you should relax
让自己
on weekends.
放松一下
Alright,
行
I'll take you up on that.
那恭敬不如从命了
Great.
好
Xiaoning?
小涂
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Jing.
静姐
What are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿啊
My relative is also hospitalized,
我亲戚也住院
coincidentally in this same hospital.
巧了就在这个医院
Isn't this the room
这不是纪总
where Mr. Ji's mother is staying?
妈妈的病房吗
Yes,
对呀
I thought I'd drop by and check on her.
我顺便过来看看阿姨
We should have asked you.
那早知道就问你了
We spent quite some time searching.
我们还找了大半天
It wasn't until Jing
还是你静姐
asked a client at the hospital
托医院的客户
that we found out the right place.
才知道领导妈妈住这儿
I just found out
我也是
about this not long ago.
刚知道
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
taking care of the boss's mom
照顾领导妈妈
isn't part of
可不是转正的
the assessment, is it?
考察指标之一吧
Mrs Ji is right inside.
阿姨就在里面
Let's go in.
进去吧
Mrs Ji,
阿姨
some colleagues are here to see you.
我们 同事过来看看您
This is Mr. Ji's mother.
这位就是纪总的妈妈
Hello, ma'am.
阿姨好
You're all so busy with work,
你们工作那么忙
yet you took the time to visit me.
还专门来看我
I hope this wouldn't be troublesome.
给你们添麻烦了
Not at all.
没事阿姨
Mr Ji thought it through thoroughly,
是纪总跟我们太客气了
so he never revealed it to us.
要是他早点告诉我们
Actually, we should have come long ago.
我们早该来过来看您了
This is a bouquet for you.
这是给您带的花
I wish you like it.
您看看
Give it to me.
给我吧
The nurse will come by later
阿姨找了护工
to tidy up.
一会儿会来收拾的吧
Right?
阿姨
Alright,
好
I'll put it over here.
放这里
Let's set these here for now.
那这东西都先放那吧
Yeah.
对
Xiaoning,
筱柠
why not
你给
introduce
阿姨
everyone to me?
介绍一下呗
Sure.
好
Well,
阿姨
they're all managers from Section 1.
这都是我们一部的
This is Ms. Rao.
这位是饶经理
Rao Jing.
饶静
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
Zhao Fanggang.
赵方刚
Ms. Tang.
唐经理
Hello, Mrs Ji.
阿姨好
That's Mr. Li and Mr. Xu.
还有李经理跟许经理
The last two are both surnamed Yao.
后面是大小姚经理
You've become managers at such a young age
这么年轻都是经理
What about you, Xiaoning?
那筱柠你呢
I'm still an assistant,
我还是助理
being assessed.
还没有转正呢
So, you're all Xiaoning's superiors.
那就都是筱柠的领导
Please take good care
那就请你们在单位
of her at work.
多照顾照顾她
This kid
我们家这孩子呀
is kind,
人呢又善良
hardworking,
又努力
and...
还
Thank you, Mrs Ji.
谢谢阿姨
I've only visited her
我就来看阿姨
a couple of times,
也就两三次吧
but she treats me like family.
阿姨把我当自己人一样
You're truly kind.
阿姨人真好
Would you like an apple?
吃苹果吗
I'm gonna peel one for you.
我给您削个苹果
Ma'am,
阿姨
I'm Mr. Ji's junior
我是纪总
from college.
大学时候的师妹
You can call me Yuhui.
您叫我羽卉就行
Hello, Yuhui.
你好啊 羽卉
I wish you a speedy recovery.
您呢就踏实地养病
If you need anything,
有什么需求呢
just let me know.
尽管跟我提
I've been friends with Mr Ji for years.
我跟师哥认识好多年了
We have a
我们两个不管是
good understanding
从工作上
in both work
还是生活上
and life.
配合都特别默契
I'm great
而且
at taking care of people.
我特别会照顾人
Oh, I wouldn't want
哪好意思
to trouble you.
让你们来照顾呀
I have
我这里呀
a caregiver here,
有护工
and Xiao...
还有筱
and Yuheng
小恒
visits often.
也一直来的
I'm managing just fine.
忙得过来
Ma'am,
阿姨
please
您啊
don't be so polite with us.
千万别跟我们见外
We're like
我们拓展一部
one big family.
就是亲如一家人
Right.
对
Isn't that right?
是不是
C'mon,
一家人
say something.
你也表个态吗
Yes, he's right.
是一家人
We're family.
我们拓展一部是一家人
But instead of
但是相比较这个
empty promises,
空有的承诺呢
I'm the kind of person
阿姨我这个人吧
who prefers to get things done.
更喜欢干点实事
Is there anything
您看您这
you need help with?
有什么需要我帮忙的吗
No, no, it's fine.
不用 不用
Don't hesitate to ask.
您不用跟我客气阿姨
Xiaoning,
筱柠
is there
你看这
anything I can help with?
有什么需要我来做的
Jing,
静姐
how about
要不
you help me...
帮我
um, get some
帮阿姨
hot water for Mrs Ji?
打点热水吧
Sure, no problem.
可以可以没问题
So,
那个 来
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理
take my bag, please.
麻烦了啊
Sure, sure.
好 好 好
I'll go get the hot water.
我去打水啊
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
I can peel the apple.
我削苹果吧
I took good care of my mom
以前我妈生病
when she's sick,
都是我照顾
so I have plenty of experience.
我特别有经验
[Thanks.]
谢谢啊
[No problem.]
不客气
Well,
阿姨
I'll help Jing with the hot water.
我帮静姐去打热水
There are no good daughters-in-law?
谁说没有孝顺儿媳妇了
C'mon, look at the lady in bed 16.
你看咱们十六床的阿姨
She's so close
跟儿媳妇
to her daughter-in-law.
比跟亲闺女都亲
That young lady comes here every day.
那小姑娘天天往这儿跑
[Even her parents visit often,]
连亲家都总来
[bringing all kinds of]
还换着花样的
[delicious food here.]
给阿姨做好吃的
[Exactly.]
是啊
[No difference today.]
今天也是
She arrived as visiting hours began.
探视一开放人就进来了
She seems to have no
周末都不安排点
leisure time on weekends.
自己的事呢
I heard that
我听说啊
she and her husband
他们两口子
both work in banks.
都在银行工作的
[Such a busy job,]
那么忙的单位
[they must be exhausted.]
也真是怪辛苦的
I happen to have work nearby,
我正好有工作路过
and it's hard to get a car at this hour.
这个时间点不太好叫车
Let me drive you.
我送你们
Sure,
好
here.
这边
Wait.
你等会儿
What's up?
干什么
I think I just saw
我刚才好像看到
Xiaoning with a guy...
小涂跟一个男的
And he
那男的
looked like our boss.
好像是咱领导
Surprise, huh?
是不是有点惊喜
I was in Jinghai for a business trip.
正好我去京海出差
I came by to check
顺便过来看看
on the shipyard deal.
造船厂谈得怎么样了
Jing!
静姐
No, no,
不用 不用
that's hot.
烫 烫 烫
Let me handle it.
我来 我来 我来
Here.
来 来
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
I've underestimated you.
我平时真是小瞧你了
What do you mean?
怎么了
Nothing.
没事
I thought you didn't care
平时我看你对这个
much about the ways of the world.
人情世故呢也不上心
Unexpectedly,
没想到
you're here to please
你来纪总母亲这儿
Mr. Ji's mother.
打亲情牌啊
I think it's hard for him
我就是看纪总他一个人
to look after
照顾母亲
his mother alone
太辛苦了
amidst his busy schedule.
顺手过来帮帮忙
I'm just doing a small favor.
没打亲情牌
Really?
这样啊
I didn't expect his mother
没想到纪总母亲
to be so seriously ill.
病这么重
No wonder he looks haggard.
怪不得他最近这么憔悴
Yeah,
是啊
making money,
要拼命赚钱
managing the dept,
又要管理部门
and caring for his mom...
还要照顾母亲
It's really tough.
是真的挺辛苦的
He is the perfect
纪总这个人呢
boyfriend
各个方面都是一个
in many ways.
完美男友的配置
But his mother
但是他现在拖着一个
does cause a burden.
这样负累的母亲
When he
如果未来
gets married,
找到另外一半结婚
this burden
这个负累就会
will be transferred
转嫁到女方身上
to his wife.
需要一起背
This cannot be considered a burden.
既然决定做一家人
Forming a family
就不能说是负累
means taking responsibilities.
更谈不上是背了吧
Sure, it's hard,
虽然过程挺辛苦的
but having someone
但是多了一个
to lean on
可以互相依靠的亲人
makes it worthwhile.
也挺幸福的
Maybe.
也许吧
But I believe in the Backpack Theory.
但我崇尚的是背包理论
Relationships are
我觉得一切的人际关系
just baggage.
都是牵绊和负担
I aim to live
我所追求的就是
without burdens,
无负无担
to travel light.
轻装上阵
Jing,
静姐
does
把
throwing away all the burdens
所有的负担都丢掉
really make you free
就真的可以自在
and happy?
和幸福吗
Xiaoning,
小涂
what are you talking about?
在聊什么呢
You are needed.
阿姨找你呢
What are you staring at?
看什么呢
Something on my face?
我脸上有花
I'm just wondering if you're a burden.
我看你是不是个负累
I saved my number in your phone,
我存了我手机号
and I've added you on WeChat.
也拿您微信加了我好友
If you need anything,
有什么事呢
just reach out.
您就尽管找我
Given my close bond with Yuheng,
以我跟师哥的关系呀
don't be too polite to me.
千万别跟我客气
It makes me so happy
昱恒有你们
that Yuheng has such
这么好的同事
good colleagues like you.
我真是很为他高兴
Should we
要不
head out now?
咱们先走吧好不好
Mrs Ji needs
这个阿姨还病着呢
more rest.
需要休息
We've already
今天耽误了
taken up a lot of her time.
这么长的时间
Ma'am, sorry to bother.
阿姨您好好休息
We'll visit
我们下次有机会
again soon.
再过来看您
[C'mon,]
不麻烦
[you're so kind.]
不麻烦了啊
[Thank you.]
谢谢啊
[Ma'am, take care.]
阿姨那您好好养病
[We'll be on our way now.]
那我们先回去了
[Thank you.]
谢谢了 好
We'll be off.
那我们就先走了
Rest well.
您好好休息
Get well soon.
早日康复阿姨
Remember
阿姨
to reach out to me.
跟我联系啊
Xiaoning,
小涂
aren't you coming?
你不走吗
Her relative
人家小涂的家人
is also in the hospital.
也生病住在这个医院
Where is she going?
她往哪走
Let's go.
赶紧走吧你
Your bag.
你的包
Hold it for me.
拿着吧你
Goodbye, ma'am.
阿姨好好休息啊
Mom,
妈
that was so close.
刚才吓死我了
I didn't expect you to react so quickly,
没想到你反应这么快
and you played your part so well.
而且演得也可好了
I was so worried
我就怕
they'd find out about our relationship.
被他们发现我们的关系
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
it's unfair that you have to
你们的关系不能公开
keep it a secret.
真是太委屈你了
Nope, it's fine.
没有
Are you talking
您是说
about Tang Yuhui?
唐羽卉吗
She is pretty great.
她是挺优秀的
But I'm not worried.
但是我不担心
I believe Yuheng
我相信昱恒
could handle this relationship
他可以把这个关系
very well.
处理得很好
Good then.
那就好
All these years,
这么多年
you're the only one
昱恒心里
in his heart.
一直就只有你
Some things
有些事
take time to see.
要慢慢去发现
Yeah?
是吗
I've noticed that
我看你最近
you've been feeling down.
情绪不大好啊
Did you have a quarrel?
是跟昱恒吵架了吗
No,
没有
not at all.
我们俩没有吵架
Then it must be
那就是工作上
a problem with work?
遇到问题了
You
你呀
shouldn't be like Yuheng,
不要学昱恒那一套
keeping everything
有什么话
bottled up inside.
都闷在心里不说
In the year
记得那一年哪
his dad passed away,
他爸爸去世
[he didn't do well on his college entrance exam.]
昱恒第一次高考失利了
He was down for a really long time.
他消沉了好长一段时间
[I really wanna comfort him.]
我是特别特别想安慰他
But he didn't say anything.
可他什么都不说
Then,
那
what happened?
然后呢
After,
后来
I don't know how,
不知道怎么
he pulled himself together
他又振作起来
[and repeated the year.]
开始复读了
[I'm not sure]
我是不晓得
if he's influenced by someone
他是受了谁的影响呢
[or he figured it out on his own.]
还是自己想通了
[But I want to tell you,]
但妈是想告诉你
in life,
人
people will always
这一辈子呀
go through
总是会经历
hardships
坎坷呀
and setbacks.
挫折呀
[No matter how tough things get,]
再难熬的事
as long as you hold on,
你只要坚持一下
you'll surely make it through.
总能熬过去的
[Fanggang,]
赵哥
[are you really not going to]
你是李总那个局
Mr. Li's dinner party?
你真不去
Yes, I am.
我真不去了
Okay, then.
好 好 好
You sure?
你真不去
Yes, totally.
我真不去了
You guys go ahead.
你们去吧
Then we'll leave now.
我们先走了啊
Okay.
好 好 好
Bye, be safe.
拜拜 路上注意安全
I'll go get my car over there.
我去那边取车
Jing.
静姐
Be careful!
慢点啊
The weather's nice.
天气不错吗
It's still early,
时间还早
let's spend the weekend together.
一起过周末吧
Did you have plans?
你有安排
I don't have any.
我没有安排啊
But even so,
那谁说没有安排
do I have to spend the weekend with you?
就得跟你一起过周末啊
What kind of gangster logic is that?
你这什么强盗思维
Here's what I thought.
我是这么想的
We spent a great
咱俩一起过年过得
New Year together.
不也挺开心的吗
Then a weekend together
那一起过个周末
might be great as well.
没准也不错
Better than being alone.
总比自己待着强吧
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理啊
are you asking me out?
你现在是在约我吗
Kind of.
算吧
Look, we're colleagues
你看啊咱俩是同事
and rivals to each other.
也是竞争对手
It might be inappropriate
约在周末见
to go out together on weekends.
不合适吧
Then,
那你
don't see me as your colleague.
你就别当咱们是同事呗
I just think
我就是觉得
[maybe we're]
咱俩没准
[suitable for each other.]
挺合适
It wouldn't be so bad
在一起搭伙过日子
if we share a life.
也不错
You want to share a life with me?
你找我搭伙过日子啊
You're not that, are you?
你不会是那个吧
What?
哪个
Want a sham marriage?
找我形婚啊
You!
你
Oh no!
完了
Gosh.
完了 完了 完了
Your reaction
看你这个表情
says something!
看你这个反应
My cab is here.
我车到了
You
你
should really take a good look
好好洗把脸
at yourself in the mirror.
照照镜子啊
I'll leave then.
我走了
[Goodbye!]]
再见
I'm blind.
我是瞎眼了
I must be blind.
我眼睛瞎了
How could I be interested in her?
我怎么能看上她呢
What's wrong with you!
不是你有病吧
Excuse me.
不好意思啊
You keep running.
你先继续跑
I'll take this call first.
我接个电话
Okay.
好
Watch your pace.
你注意节奏啊
Hello, dad.
喂 爸
Why haven't you returned my massages?
你怎么都不回我消息啊
Nothing much.
也没什么事
Just checking in on you.
就是关心关心你吗
Listen to me,
想跟你说呀
don't forget to take care of yourself
你忙碌工作的同时
while you're busy with work.
也要好好注意身体
Right,
对了
I haven't told you yet.
我还没跟你说呢
Qi Yu
齐郁
has passed the police exam.
他考上警察了
[Although I knew that]
虽然我早就知道
he would definitely make it.
他一定能考上的
Okay, then.
行好了
I should go now.
先不跟你说了啊
Bye.
拜拜
I'm coming!
我来啦
Let's go!
走喽
Be careful!
慢点
You transferred money to me?
你给我转钱了
I saw the reminder on your account
我看到你的花宝
about the repayment.
还款提醒了
We're not short on money, you know...
咱又不差那钱欠它干吗
I've made a repayment plan.
我都做完还款计划了
I don't need your money.
不用你给我转
Don't make me feel
咱俩之间
I'm being treated as a stranger.
还分什么你我啊
I just don't want you to be too tired,
我就是不想让你太累
[and to deal with]
去承受这些
unnecessary stress.
没必要的压力
What,
怎么了
are you upset?
不开心了
No,
没有
I just wanted to pay this debt myself.
我就是想这个钱自己还
Okay then.
行吧
Don't overthink it, I just wanna
我就是不想让你太累
share your pressure.
没别的意思
Do you want wagyu for dinner tonight?
要不要去吃和牛呀晚上
A friend of mine
我有个朋友
opened a new wagyu restaurant.
新开了一个和牛店
There's a sale today.
今天打折呢
I planned to order some ingredients and
我本来想订几个菜
cook you some of my specialties.
回家给你做拿手菜吃呢
How can that be?
那怎么行
You almost ran for a day.
你今天跑步累了一天
Cook yourself?
还要自己做饭
I can't bear to let you do that.
我可舍不得
People who wanna
我跟你说啊
go to this restaurant must
这家店要是别人去呢
make a reservation 1 week in advance.
都要提前一周预订呢
I'll better hurry and
我还得赶紧跟我朋友
text my friend.
发个消息
Fine,
好
as long as you like it.
你喜欢我们就吃呗
[He pulled himself together]
他又振作起来
[and repeated the year.]
开始复读了
[I'm not sure]
我是不晓得
[if he's influenced by someone]
他是受了谁的影响呢
[or he figured it out on his own.]
还是自己想通了
[Could this be]
会是他心里
[the girl he kept]
一直记挂着的
[in his mind all along?]
那个女孩吗
Xiaoning,
筱柠
let's go.
走吧
The visiting hours are over.
探望的时间已经过了
You can't go in anymore.
你不能进去了
I just came from Zhouyang.
我刚从洲洋那边过来
I got stuck
路上有事故
in an accident.
堵车了
Next time if you don't think
下次要是觉得
you'll make it in time,
时间不行的话
then don't say yes to your mom.
就别答应妈
She's been eagerly
她眼巴巴地
waiting for you all day.
盼着你一天呢
I'm sorry.
对不起啊
I sent you messages on WeChat,
我给你发微信
did you not see them?
你是没看到吗
I did.
我看到了
Then why didn't you reply?
那为什么不回啊
I...
我
Hello, Dr Zhou.
喂 周医生
[Your mom's results]
你母亲的检查报告
came out.
出来了
We held
我们和几位
a consultation with
相关科室的主任
other dept heads
做了会诊
and reviewed
一起看了
all of her health metrics.
你母亲的各项身体指标
How were her results?
那她结果怎么样
Is her condition
身体
suitable for that special medication?
适合用那个特效药吗
[Everyone agreed that]
大家一致都认为
[based on her current state,]
根据你母亲目前的状况
[this medication]
这个药
[is something that can be tried.]
是完全可以试一试的
That's great!
那太好了
Then
那
when can
我妈妈她
it be used
什么时候可以
on my mom?
开始用这个药啊
[Next week.]
下周就可以
However,
不过
I have to remind you that
我还是要提醒你一句
it's entirely out-of-pocket,
这个药全部自费
It's quite expensive.
而且价格不菲
[And no one]
用完之后
[can say for sure]
能起到什么样的效果
[what the results will be.]
谁也不好说
[So you should]
所以你们自己
[talk it through among yourselves.]
要好好商量一下
We must try.
当然要用了
We will use it.
我们用这个药
Could you please
周医生
arrange this as soon as possible?
麻烦您尽快安排一下
Thank you!
谢谢啊
[Okay.]
好
Your hair is so long now,
头发都这么长了
doesn't it get in your eyes?
不遮眼睛啊
A bit.
有一点
So disheveled.
不修边幅
How do you go see mom
这么长的头发
with hair this long?
怎么去见妈妈
Aren't you embarrassed?
你好意思呀
I don't have time to think about these.
确实无暇顾及这些了
How is it?
怎么样
Looks good.
我觉得还不错
It should be fine for now.
先这样吧
You can go to a barber
等有时间了
when you have time.
再去外面剪
The lady in the bad next to mom
妈隔壁床的那个阿姨
passed away today.
今天去世了
Her son cried the whole time,
她儿子过来了
saying that he didn't
一直哭着说
get to see his mom one last time.
没有见到妈妈最后一面
Mom was pretty upset.
我看妈挺伤心
But not just her,
别说妈了
I felt the same way.
我也伤心
I understand that now you're
我很理解你现在
busy working to earn money
忙着工作赚钱
for her treatment.
给妈治病
But I'm also afraid that,
但是我也害怕
one day,
万一有一天
after she passed away,
妈妈百年以后
[you would]
你因为
[regret not spending more time with her.]
没有长时间陪她后悔
I wanna
那所以
discuss something with you.
我想跟你商量件事
Why don't we sell the house?
要不咱们把房子卖了吧
[Then, you don't have to]
这样就不用担心
[worry about the money.]
治病的钱了
And you'll have more time
你就有更多的时间
to keep mom company.
陪妈妈了
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样
I'm sorry.
对不起啊
I haven't been
这段时间
performing well lately,
确实是我不好
but avoid something.
是我一直在逃避
You know, mom really
妈妈现在的情况
needs emotional support now.
很需要精神支柱的
Shouldn't she be the most scared one?
现在最害怕的不是她吗
We should
我们应该
make her feel more secure.
给她足够的安全感
But her emotional support
但她的精神支柱
is you.
就是你啊
[Plus,]
再说
[this time is different.]
现在跟以前不一样了
[When dad passed away,]
爸去世的时候
[you were alone.]
你是一个人
But I'm by your side now.
你现在有我了
No matter what,
不管什么时候
I won't leave you alone.
我都不会让你一个人的
I'll be there for you
我会陪着你
and keep you company.
不会让你觉得孤单的
We don't have to
房子
sell the house.
不用卖
And no worries
钱的问题
about money.
你也不需要考虑
Leave it all to me.
都交给我就好
And I also promise you,
我也答应你
I will go to the hospital
这段时间
more often lately.
我会多去医院的
Good.
好
However,
倒是你
you should focus on
得多关心一下
your client development more.
客户开发的问题
[You've worked]
之前的时候
[so hard and]
一直都那么努力
[gone through hardships.]
受了那么多苦
[But now,]
现在呢
[you're gonna give up]
就因为一点挫折
'cause of a minor setback?
要放弃吗
This isn't the way
这可不是你
you do things.
涂筱柠的风格
I got it.
我知道了
Here.
来
How is it?
怎么样
Are you satisfied?
看看还满意吗
It looks
看起来
pretty good.
还不错
You also need to pay more attention
这些小微企业
to these microenterprises.
你也得上上心
Okay.
嗯
[Besides these civilian-run enterprises,]
除了这些民营企业之外
pay extra attention
小微企业
to microenterprises.
得着重关注一下
[No problem.]
没问题
Xiaoning,
小涂
busy working?
在忙呢
Miss Rao.
饶经理
Xiaoning.
筱柠啊
You suddenly
前段时间
lost interest in
你好像对营销客户
customer marketing.
失去了兴趣
[Did you]
你是不是
know that
知道
something would happen sooner or later?
早晚都会发生点什么
Jing,
静姐
what do you mean?
什么意思呀
Er,
这个
what's important
早晚会发生什么
is not what will happen
都不重要
in the future,
重要的是呢
but that you step by step
你要按部就班
do your current job well.
做好现在的工作
Understand?
明白吗
Yes, ma'am.
明白
Good then.
明白就行
After visiting the hospital,
从医院回来
I've been curious
我就一直在琢磨
whether our boss
领导跟小唐
is dating Yuhui.
不会真的在一起了吧
She's
你看啊
so attentive and caring
在医院的时候
with Mrs Ji
小唐对领导的妈妈
at the hospital,
多热情 多照顾
covering her with blankets
又是盖被子
and peeling fruit for her...
又是削水果
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理呀
you asked me out
你把我叫出来
just to tell me this?
就是为了说这事啊
Could you perhaps
咱就是说你能不能
have a bit more imagination?
有点想象力呢
No,
不是
I've been thinking
我是一直在琢磨
that maybe our company's rules
咱们公司这个制度
are a bit inhumane.
多少有点反人性
Look,
你看啊
Liu Xiaoli from Section 2 has been
那二部的刘晓莉
transferred for almost half a year.
都调走快半年了
It really is.
这确实如此
The rules
这公司制度
are indeed inhumane.
是有点反人性
It's not because of this that
你该不是因为这个
you don't want to be with me, right?
才不跟我搭伙过日子吧
Don't have to worry about this at all.
这个你完全不用担心
I specifically looked into it before.
我之前专门了解过
No clear prohibition
我们公司
on boyfriends and girlfriends
并没有明确禁止
working together.
情侣同岗
[Liu Xiaoli]
二部的刘晓莉
was transferred
是领完证之后
after she got married.
才被调走的
Continue.
来你继续
If you agree
再者说
to be my girlfriend,
我们两个人
we need time
真的决定要在一起
to get to know each other better.
那还要先相处相处看看
[No need to overthink it.]
没必要想那么多
As for our work,
工作上面的事情吧
we should take it
走一步
as it comes.
看一步
Mr Zhao,
不是赵经理
you specifically looked into it?
你还专门去了解过呀
Yes, I did.
专门了解过
So, you're not just
那我看这意思是以后
messing around.
不光走肾
You're serious.
咱直接走心啊
I'm not one of your young guys.
我又不是你那些弟弟
I'm already in my thirties.
三十好几了
How can I joke about
怎么可能
relationships?
拿感情闹着玩呢
I know,
我知道啊
entering a relationship
产生一段感情
will add weight to your burden
会让你的背包增重
[and]
还会
[make you feel a bit]
让你有一部分的
[constrained.]
约束感
But it won't
但同样
make you feel lonely
它不会让你
for the rest of your life, right?
孤独一生老无所依吗
[We should embrace it bravely,]
我们要勇敢地打开它
and accept
接纳
all the beauty this world has to offer.
这个世界一切的美好
But have you ever
但是赵经理
thought about how to
你有没有想过
make sure that
你怎么能保证
all those packed in my backpack
装进我背包里的东西
won't be taken away in the end?
最后不会被全部拿走呢
[Sincerity is the key.]
心诚则灵
Mrs Ji will surely be safe and sound.
阿姨一定会平平安安的
Thank you.
谢谢啊
She will!
会的
Ji Yuheng didn't give up.
纪昱恒没有放弃
Mom didn't give up either.
妈妈也没有放弃
I definitely shouldn't give up.
我更不能放弃
I should
我呢
have some confidence and faith.
得有这个自信和信心
Then, when I'm at the hospital,
这样我陪在医院的时候
I can pass on a lot of emotional strength
才能给妈妈传递很多
to her.
精神力量
I feel
感觉
that time truly flies by.
时间真的过得好快
In the blink of an eye, we're already
一眨眼我们居然也是要
approaching our thirties.
奔三的人了
I feel like just yesterday
还感觉昨天
we were still little kids.
我们都是小孩呢
How could we
怎么会要
have to deal with these?
经历跟承受这些
Alright, forget it.
先不想这些
How's it going with your clients?
你那客户的事怎么样了
Fanggang
小赵哥
introduced me to several groups
给我介绍了几组
from the Tech Park,
园区的客户
and I'm talking with them now.
我也都在接洽中
Before,
之前呢
I was indeed impatient and short-sighted.
是有点急功近利
Then I started to doubt myself.
后来开始自我怀疑
Now I understand.
现在我也想明白了
I should take it easy.
慢慢来
There's no hurry.
不着急
That's good.
怕什么
After all no matter what,
反正不管怎么样
my dad has got your back.
还有我爸给你兜底呢
I can't just
我也不能
always count on your dad.
总指望着叔叔吧
What if I get the permanent position?
万一要是我转正了呢
Will I still
我还指着
count on your dad?
叔叔给我兜底啊
Take all the help that you can get.
能兜一次是一次喽
After all, your business
反正你们银行的业务
is just about
不也就是
giving loans and attracting deposits.
放贷款跟拉存款
Since my dad
那我爸的钱
has to do that,
找谁借不是借
why didn't he choose you?
找谁存不是存呢
There's no need.
不用
What,
怎么了
don't you have any faith in me?
你对我一点信心没有啊
Of course I do.
有 有 有
You'll surely get it.
你这次肯定没问题
Let's go.
走吧
The results are good.
结果还是不错的
Really?
真的吗
[After using the medication,]
用了药之后
[the previously metastasized lesions]
原先几处转移的病灶
[have shrunk in several areas.]
有所缩小
Currently, it looks like
目前看起来
the condition is well under control.
控制得还是不错的
So,
那医生
can continuous use
是不是我妈妈
of it improve
只要持续用药的话
her condition?
身体能越来越好啊
Actually,
这个
it's hard to say.
很难说
[With every medication,]
任何药物到了最后
[drug resistance is inevitable]
都会不可避免地出现
[in the end.]
耐药的问题
[But don't worry.]
不过你们放心
The current situation
病人目前的状况
is quite good.
还是不错的
If remains stable,
按照这个态势维持的话
getting discharged
想要出院
and going home to rest
回家休养
shouldn't be a problem.
不是什么大问题
Thank you.
谢谢您了
Come,
来
gather around.
大家集合了
We're having the midterm exam today.
今天咱们体育期中考
Class One will go first.
一班先来
[Okay.]
好
[Chop chop.]
快点 快点
No worries, sir.
没关系老师
I'm fine on my own.
我自己就好
I think he's on his own.
他好像一个人
Who wants to team up with Ji Yuheng?
谁跟纪昱恒一组
Come hold his ankles.
过来帮他压压脚踝
I won't.
我不要
Me neither.
我也不要
His dad used his friends like that.
他爸那样坑朋友
Who dares to have anything to do with him?
谁还敢跟他打交道啊
[Yeah.]
对呀
What happened to his dad?
他爸怎么了
Something bad.
他爸好像出事了
[Anyone?]
有没有人
Sir,
老师
can I?
我行吗
Sure,
好
come.
来吧
[Okay, get ready.]
好 大家准备了啊
[Three,]
三
[two,]
二
[one.]
一